<chapter id="ccc-Item-States">
	<title>Item States</title>
	
	<para>
		This chapter provides an overview about the states of canvas items.
	</para>
		
	<para>
		There are several states that items want to <!-- FIXME -->
	</para>

	<sect1 id="ccc-State-Propagation">
		<title>State Propagation</title>

		<para>
			State propagation is an important part of the item state
			concept. Its the part of the internals that tell parent
			items (and views) that a state has changed and views can
			easily act on this notification (eg. cancel current
			redraw requests and resume them once the canvas is ready).
		</para>

		<formalpara>
			<title>State Signalling</title>
			State propagation is quite easy. It's all handled in the CcItem
			<!-- FIXME add link --> class. States can be (un)set per view.
			If the style changes for a view, the parent item picks up this
			change and changes its own state. This mechanism is executed
			synchronously (but might be changed to a very high priority
			idle handler).
		</formalpara>

		<formalpara>
			<title>State Processing</title>
		</formalpara>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="ccc-State-Collecting">
		<title>Collecting</title>

		<para>
			CCC is supposed to get a feature called <ulink
			url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=379823">Item
			Clustering</ulink>. The state of updating the clusters will
			be specifyable.
		</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="ccc-State-Size-Request">
		<title>Size Requests</title>

		<para>
			Size requests are not yet implemented in CCC. But the state
			of managing size requests and size allocations will be
			specifyable.
		</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="ccc-State-Preparing">
		<title>Preparing</title>

		<para>
			Not every item will update every detail just when an internal
			attribute changes (eg. the text item doesn't update the caret
			position immediately once the cursor position changes).
		</para>

		<para>
			Items in this state shouldn't be drawn as they are in an
			intermediate state that needs to be passed to be renderable.
		</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="ccc-State-Disposing">
		<title>Disposing</title>

		<para>
			As a part of the GObject memory management system…
		</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
